(
"ai_sub_version": "1.9.2",
"subtitles_prompt_version": 2,
"complete": true,
"max_retries_exceeded": false,
"settings": (
"ai": (
"model": "gemini-cli:gemini-3-flash-preview",
"rpm": 4,
"tpm": 250000,
"google": (
"file_cache_ttl": 10,
"use_files_api": true
),
"gemini_cli": (
"timeout": 600
)
),
"split": (
"max_seconds": 300,
"re_encode": (
"enabled": true,
"fps": 1,
"height": 360,
"bitrate_kb": 35,
"encoder": "libx264"
)
),
"thread": (
"uploads": 4,
"re_encode": 2,
"subtitles": 8
),
"retry": (
"run": 3,
"max": 9,
"delay": 30
),
"log": (
"level": "info",
"timestamps": false,
"scrub": true
)
湊あくあ 2nd 3D LIVE
あくあ色 3rd Anniversary Live
Minato Aqua 2nd 3D LIVE
Aqua Iro 3rd Anniversary Live
YouTube無料ライブ開催決定！
Free YouTube Live confirmed!
湊あくあ デビュー3周年を記念した
3Dライブ第2弾！
Celebrating Minato Aqua's 3rd Anniversary,
her second solo 3D Live!
2021年8月9日(Mon) 開催！
Holding on August 9, 2021 (Mon)!
2018.08.08 Debut!!
全ロスしました...
I lost everything...
100万人突破まで走り続ける
I'll keep running until I hit 1 million subscribers
90万人 行こうぜ!
Let's go for 900,000!
2021.08.08 湊あくあ デビュー3周年
2021.08.08 Minato Aqua 3rd Anniversary
ご主人のおかげで色んな景色をみてきました！
Thanks to my Masters, I've seen many wonderful sights!
チャンネル登録者数100万人達成ありがとう!!
Thank you for reaching 1 million subscribers!!
このさきもずっと、たくさんの思い出を一緒にかさねていこう
Let's keep making many more memories together from now on.
感謝の気持ちを込めて...
With a heart full of gratitude...
何をしても不器用で
I'm clumsy no matter what I do
何かとミスしてばっか
Always making mistakes somehow
ダメダメな私だって
Even for a good-for-nothing like me
できることがあるの
There are things I can do
へこんで悲しくたって
Even if I'm feeling down and sad
笑顔にしてあげるんだ
I'm going to make you smile
ここにいるから早く
Since I'm right here, hurry up
私を見つけてね
And find me
Love You Love You Oh Oh
I Love You So Much
I Love You Oh Oh
Love You Love You Oh Oh
愛してるもーん！
I love you!
いつでも隣にいるし
I'm always by your side
いつでも一緒に笑える
We can always laugh together
私をたくさん知って
Get to know me a lot
たくさん好きって言って
And tell me you love me a lot
わがままで朝も苦手
Selfish and bad at mornings
ドジだしダメダメだけど
Clumsy and good-for-nothing, but
それでも私のことを
Even so, please keep
見ててね
Watching me
描く夢の未来へ続く
Continuing to the future of the dream I draw
道も
Even the path,
君と
with you,
歩けますように
I hope to walk.
ねぇ もっと好きになってもらいたいな
Hey, I want you to like me even more
頭の中は君ばっかっていうか
My head is full of nothing but you
そっぽなんて向いてないで
Don't look the other way
あぁもうヤキモチしちゃうわ あぁ
Ah, I'm getting jealous, ah
ずっとずっと好きがいいの
I want to love you forever and ever
心の奥まで閉じちゃうくらいに
Enough to lock up the depths of my heart
こっち向いてってよねぇ ダーリン
Look this way, hey darling
あぁもう離さないから 絶対に
Ah, I'll never let go, never
君がいるから私いつでも
Because you're here, I can always
頑張れるんだ
keep doing my best
落ち込んで悲しくたって
Even when I'm feeling down or sad
君がいるから
because you're here
今日は3周年3Dライブに来てくれてありがとう！
Thank you for coming to my 3rd anniversary 3D live today!
あくあ色に染まれー！
Be dyed in Aqua's colors!
君がいるから歩いてこれた
I was able to walk this far because you're here
君がいなくちゃ前も見れない
Without you, I can't even look ahead
嫌なこととか辛いこととかあったって
Even when bad things or hard things happen
君の力でここまで笑ってこれたんだ
I've been able to laugh this much thanks to your strength
今度はもっと私がぐっと引っ張って
Next time, I'll pull you along even more
連れて行くんだ
and take you with me
君がいるから私がいるの
I exist because you're here
こんな私を愛してくれるの？
Will you love someone like me?
ねぇ もっと まだもっと 受け止めてよねぇ
Hey, more, even more, accept me, okay?
ねぇいい？ さぁ声を上げて
Hey, is it okay? Come on, raise your voice
ねぇ もっと 好きになってもらいたいな
Hey, I want you to like me even more
いつでもそう私ばっかみたいに
It's always just me, like...
そっぽなんて向かせないわ
I won't let you look the other way
ねぇほら夢中にしちゃうわ あぁ
Hey look, I'll make you obsessed, ah
ずっとずっと好きがいいの
I want to love you forever and ever
心も体も染まっちゃうくらいに
Enough to be dyed, heart and soul
こっち向いてってよねぇ ダーリン
Look this way, hey darling
あぁもう離さないから 絶対に
Ah, I'll never let go, never
絶対ね
Promise me
絶対よ
I mean it
約束だよ
It's a promise
愛しちゃうもっと
I'll love you even more
おねがいダーリン
作詞/作曲：ナナホシ管弦楽団
Please Darling
Lyrics/Composition: Nanahoshi Orchestra
おねがいダーリン見て聞いて欲しいの
Please Darling, I want you to look and listen
ダーリン あなた私のこと全然聞かない
Darling, you don't listen to me at all
あれほどやめてって言ったタバコもお酒も
Neither the cigarettes nor the alcohol I told you to stop
毎日さかんな遊びも一日たりとも欠かさず
Playing around so much every day, without missing a single day
肝臓労わって欲しいなんてお願いしても
Even if I ask you to take care of your liver
完了してあげないんだから
I'm not going to finish it for you
ああ言えばこう言うこと聞かない あなたのハートは真っ黒です
You always have a comeback and don't listen, your heart is pitch black
言いたいことは言わないし
You don't say what you want to say
行きたいところへも連れて行ってくれない
And you don't take me where I want to go
ねぇ そんなのバカみたいじゃない
Hey, isn't that just stupid?
そうじゃない じゃない じゃない
That's not it, not it, not it
いつも思わせぶりな感じで
Always with that suggestive vibe
察して欲しい感じで
With that 'I want you to figure it out' vibe
わざと口にしないの ずるくない？
Purposely not saying it, isn't that unfair?
バカじゃないの？
Are you an idiot?
おねがいダーリン見て聞いて欲しいのは
Please Darling, what I want you to look and listen to is
形のないもの
something without form
馬鹿にしないで見て聞いて覗いてよ
Don't make fun of me, look, listen, and peek in
瞳の奥の方
at the depths of my eyes
まっすぐ見つめて
Stare straight at me
おねがいダーリンしてみて欲しいの
Please Darling, I want you to try it
ダーリン 私はあなたの気持ちを全然知らないわ
Darling, I don't know your feelings at all
あれほど健気に見つめてきたのに
Even though I've been looking at you so admirably
今ではすっかり知らんぷり
Now you're completely ignoring me
って言うかそれって胡座かいてるだけなんじゃないですか？ぶっちゃけ
I mean, isn't that just you being complacent? To be blunt
四六時中あなたのせいで私のハートはボロボロです
My heart is in tatters 24/7 because of you
つれない時はつれないし
When you're cold, you're cold
意地悪ばかり言うから いつも私は風邪気味
Because you only say mean things, I'm always feeling a bit under the weather
ねぇ 何だかバカみたいじゃない
Hey, isn't that just kind of stupid?
そうじゃない じゃない じゃない
That's not it, not it, not it
どこか足元見てる感じで
Like you're looking down on me somehow
値踏みされてる感じで
Like you're appraising me
駆け引きやだ、勝ち負けじゃなくない？
No more games, it's not about winning or losing, right?
そういうめんどくさいことしてるからめんどくさいことになるんだよ
It's because you do such annoying things that it becomes annoying.
寡黙なダーリン、ねぇ聞いて、切なさは飾りじゃないのよ
Silent Darling, hey, listen, this sadness isn't just for show.
よそ見しないで、逃げないで、触ってよ、心の奥の方
Don't look away, don't run away, touch the depths of my heart.
一瞬のことじゃない、おねだりしてみてはくれないの？
It's not just for a moment, won't you try asking me for something?
言葉にできない臆病さは、したたかさではないのよ
Cowardice that can't be put into words isn't the same as being calculating.
甘えてないで、口に出してよ
Don't just depend on me, say it out loud.
もう、ちゃんとこっち向いてったら
Geez, look at me properly.
おねがいダーリン、見て聞いて、欲しいのはカタチのないもの
Please Darling, look and listen, what I want is something without a form.
馬鹿にしないで、見て聞いて、覗いてよ、瞳の奥の方
Don't make fun of me, look and listen, peer into the depths of my eyes.
寡黙なダーリン、寝てないで、暴いてよ、私の素顔
Silent Darling, don't sleep, uncover my true self.
おねがいダーリン、そばにいて、触らせて、心の奥の方
Please Darling, stay by my side, let me touch the depths of your heart.
まっすぐ見つめて、おねだりしてみてほしいの
Look straight at me, I want you to try asking me for something.
おねがいダーリン
Please, Darling.
改めまして、こんあくあー！湊あくあでーす！
Once again, kon-aqua! I'm Minato Aqua!
みんなー！元気ーーー！？
Everyone! Are you doing well!?
といいつつ、水を。
Having said that, some water.
ぷはっ！ということで、あ、今のはね、あの、
Phew! So, ah, that was...
素直な人にしか見えない水でございます。
...water that can only be seen by honest people.
みんなにはきっと見えたと思うんだけれども！
I'm sure you all could see it!
はい！ということで、ついに始まりましたー！
Alright! So, it has finally begun!
湊あくあ3Dライブ、あくあ色 3rd Anniversary Liveということで、
Minato Aqua's 3D Live, 'Aqua-iro 3rd Anniversary Live'!
3周年でーーーす！！！
It's my 3rd anniversary!!!
8月の8日に、私、湊あくあ、3周年を迎えましたー！ありがとう！
On August 8th, I, Minato Aqua, reached my 3rd anniversary! Thank you!
当日ね、昨日の8月の8日は、
On that day, yesterday, August 8th...
今日こうしてね、このライブを、パーッと、すっごいライブをするためにね、
...to put on this amazing, spectacular live show today...
ちょっと、準備を、準備を、準備をしてね、
...I was busy with preparation after preparation.
次の日の9日にライブをさせていただくってことになったんだけれども！
So it was decided that I'd hold the live on the following day, the 9th!
今日はね、5月に続けて3Dライブを開催して、
Following May, I'm holding another 3D live today.
2回目のYouTube無料3Dライブなんだけれども！
This is the second free 3D live on YouTube!
ダンスレッスンしたり、いろんな準備とかを進めてきました！
I've been taking dance lessons and doing all sorts of preparations!
みんな、ワクワクしてますかー！？
Everyone, are you excited!?
ワクワクしてますかー！？
Are you excited!?
私はね、もうね、やばいよ。ワクワクが止まんないよ！
I am, seriously. I can't stop being excited!
で、なんかね、もうね、みんなね、この1年いろんなことがあって、
And, you know, everyone, so much has happened this past year.
おかげさまでね、配信以外でもね、いろんな活動をさせていただいておりまして、
Thanks to you, I've been able to do various activities outside of streaming as well.
いや本当に応援してくださってありがとうございます！ありがとうございます！
Seriously, thank you so much for your support! Thank you!
そんな日頃の感謝を込めて、今日は短い時間ではありますが、
With all my daily gratitude, though it's a short time today...
アイドル、銀河一アイドルの湊あくあをお届けするので、
I'll be bringing you the galaxy's #1 idol, Minato Aqua!
みんな最後までついてきてくれると嬉しいでーーーす！
I'd be happy if you all stick with me until the end!
ちなみにね、ちょっと、おれ、なんか5月と同じじゃない？
By the way, some of you might be thinking, "Wait, isn't this the same as May?"
って思った人いるかもしれないけど、ちょっと待ってねって！
But just wait a second!
ちゃんと、今日の日のために、いろんなもの準備してるので、
I've prepared all sorts of things specifically for today.
お楽しみいただけたら嬉しいなって思ってます！
I hope you enjoy it!
そして、このライブのあと、前回の5月にやってすごい好評だった、
Also, after this live, just like in May which was very well-received...
メンバーシップ限定の生放送があります！
...there will be a membership-only livestream!
なので、メンバーの方はライブが終わったら見てくれると嬉しいです！
So members, I'd be happy if you watch it after the live ends!
で、メンバーじゃないって人はね、この機会にぜひね、
And for those who aren't members, please take this opportunity...
今が湊あくあのメンバーシップに、こっちかな？こっちかな？
...to join Minato Aqua's membership! This way? Or this way?
メンバーシップになって、一緒に3Dのメン限ライブ見てくれると嬉しいです！
Become a member and watch the 3D members-only live with us!
あ、そんなライブというほどのものではないですけど、色々お喋りしましょう！
Ah, it's not really a big live show, but let's chat about various things!
それじゃあ次、私が初めての歌ってみた動画で歌った、
Alright, next up, the song I sang in my very first "Tried Singing" video...
あの曲、聴いて...
Please listen to that song...
待っていてください！
Please wait for it!
インドア系ならトラックメイカー
'Indoor-kei Nara Trackmaker'.
Indoor-kei Nara Trackmaker
My house
it's a bubble
new house
electro house
トラックメイカー
Trackmaker
通勤ラッシュ
Commuter rush
アップなロードは
Uploads are
テンションマックス
Tension max
ハウスダスト
House dust
ノーフィクション
No fiction
花粉症には
For hay fever
マスクメロン
Muskmelon
カーソル待ってよ
Wait for the cursor
クラクション
Claxon
ほら
See
クリック
Click
リリック
Lyric
トラックメイカー
Trackmaker
オシャレの極致だ
It's the height of fashion
両手を掲げて
Raise both hands
ジョージにワイシャツ
George in a dress shirt
MIDI
オシャレの聖地だ
It's the holy land of fashion
両手を掲げて
Raise both hands
納期は明日だ
The deadline is tomorrow
エビデイ エビナイ トラックメイカー
Every day, every night, trackmaker
トラックメイカー
Trackmaker
クラップヘンザ
Clap hands up
トラックメイカー
Trackmaker
クラップヘンザ
Clap hands up
ドリカムコンプの
DREAMS COME TRUE compressor's
ツルってタップ
Smoothly tap
ホップでステップ
Hop and step
ダブステップ
Dubstep
フロアのアイツは
That guy on the floor is
ロボットダンス
Robot dancing
お酒も入って
Having some drinks
そこそこナイス
Feeling pretty nice
ネクタイ緩めた
Loosened his tie
今こそチャンス
Now's the chance
黒縁メガネに
Black-rimmed glasses
細身のパンツ
Slim-fit pants
二人を揺らすは
Shaking us both is
ブールベース
Bull base
今夜も残念極彩色です
Tonight is also unfortunately colorful
オシャレの極致だ
It's the height of fashion
両手を掲げて
Raise both hands
ジョージにジャージも
George in a jersey too
インドア系ならトラックメイカー
If you're the indoor type, trackmaker
オシャレの聖地だ
It's the holy land of fashion
両手を掲げて
Raise both hands
ピークを抑えろ
Control the peak
眠気のピークにカフェイン投下
Caffeine drop at the peak of sleepiness
眠気のピークにカフェイン投下ー！
Caffeine drop at the peak of sleepiness!
オシャレの極致だ
It's the height of fashion
両手を掲げて
Raise both hands
ジョージにワイシャツ
George in a dress shirt
MIDI
オシャレの聖地だ
It's the holy land of fashion
両手を掲げて
Raise both hands
納期は明日だ
The deadline is tomorrow
エビデイ エビナイ トラックメイカー
Every day, every night, trackmaker
オシャレの極致だ
It's the height of fashion
両手を掲げて
Raise both hands
ジョージにワイシャツ
George in a dress shirt
MIDI
オシャレの聖地だ
It's the holy land of fashion
両手を掲げて
Raise both hands
納期は明日だ
The deadline is tomorrow
エビデイ エビナイ トラックメイカー
Every day, every night, trackmaker
ファッションセンター
Fashion center
クラップヘンザ
Clap hands up
ファッションセンター
Fashion center
クラップヘンザ
Clap hands up
ファッションセンター
Fashion center
クラップヘンザ
Clap hands up
Ubiquitous dB
I'm not
ボリューム 邪魔？
Volume... in the way?
まだ足りない デシベル上げて
Still not enough, turn up the decibels
世界はドメイン 境界線はもう
The world's a domain, the boundary lines
どこにもない
are nowhere to be found
感情の振動を まんま伝えるよ
I'll convey the vibrations of emotion just as they are
答えてよ 七色の
Answer me, the seven colors of
エモーショングラフィ
Emotiongraphy
君に
To you
届いているかな
I wonder if it's reaching you
もっと 聴かせてよ
Let me hear it more
感性的な信号
Sensitive signals
...パルテクニカ
...Paltechnika
見つけてみて
Try to find me
声の中の
Within my voice
ピュアな宝物
A pure treasure
鳴らせハイファイな想いと
Let high-fidelity feelings ring out
次元を超え胸打つメロディ
A melody crossing dimensions that strikes the heart
そしてリアルな秘密教えよう
And let me tell you a real secret
この歌は永遠に生きてくよ
This song will live on forever
だから逢いたいなんてナンセンス
So, wanting to meet is nonsense
ユビキタスするよ君のメモリに
I'll be ubiquitous in your memory
ほら
Look
君が私を呼ぶのなら
If you call for me
耳澄まして
Listen closely
繊細に響け　超常現象だから
Resonate delicately, because it's a paranormal phenomenon
デシベル上げて
Raise the decibels
独りきりだなんて壁はもう
Walls like being all alone
通用しない
No longer work
一緒に揺れて　それが歌だから
Sway with me, because that's what a song is
託してよ
Entrust it to me
共鳴機能
Resonance function
エモーションレスキュー
Emotion rescue
君にちゃんと見えるかな
I wonder if you can see me properly
もっと手を振って
Wave your hands more
感情的鑑賞はダイレクトに
Emotional appreciation is direct
見つけた　点滅してる
I found it, it's blinking
それが君の
That is your
ピュアな宝物
Pure treasure
響けアッパーなリズムで
Resonate with an upbeat rhythm
強制的に上げていくハートビート
Forcibly raising the heartbeat
強引でもぜひ聴いてほしいんだ
Even if it's forceful, I want you to listen
君のためだけに歌うから
Because I sing just for you
なぜかちょっと泣けちゃって
For some reason, I cried a bit
君が笑ってくれたせいだけなんだ
It's all because you smiled at me
そっか
I see
通じ合える温かさは
This warmth of mutual understanding
初めてかな
Is it the first time?
ここはどこでしょう
Where is this place?
私は誰でしょう
Who am I?
声を頼りに探してよ
Find me by relying on my voice
心で歌うよ
I sing with my heart
心に届いてほしいよ
I want it to reach your heart
夢もリアルも
Both dreams and reality
本当だよ
Are real
鳴らせハイファイな想いと
Let high-fidelity feelings ring out
次元を超え胸打つメロディ
A melody crossing dimensions that strikes the heart
そしてリアルな秘密教えよう
And let me tell you a real secret
この歌は永遠に生きてくよ
This song will live on forever
だから逢いたいなんてナンセンス
So, wanting to meet is nonsense
ユビキタスするよ君のメモリに
I'll be ubiquitous in your memory
ほら
Look
君が私を呼ぶのなら
If you call for me
耳澄まして
Listen closely
いつも　そばにいるよ
I'm always by your side
デシベルを上げて
Turn up the decibels
One, two!
グッバイ宣言
作詞/作曲：Chinozo
Goodbye Sengen
Lyrics/Composition: Chinozo
エマージェンシー　零時
Emergency, midnight
奴らはクレイジー・イン・ザ・タウン
They're crazy in the town
家に籠ってゴロゴロ　ゴロゴロと
Staying home, idling about
堕落の夜に耽り耽る
Indulging in a night of depravity
ルルル　放つ言葉はルルル
Lululu, the words I release are lululu
腐っていた
They were rotten
正論も常識も
Goodbye to a city where
意味を持たない都会にサヨウナラ
logic and common sense mean nothing
引きこもり絶対ジャスティス
Shutting oneself away is absolute justice
俺の私だけの檻の中で
Inside a cage just for me
聴き殺してランデブー
A rendezvous of listening to death
俺の私の音が響くまで
Until my sounds resonate
引きこもり絶対ジャスティス
Shutting oneself away is absolute justice
俺の私だけの檻の中で
Inside a cage just for me
聴き殺してランデブー
A rendezvous of listening to death
俺の私の音を君が包むだけ
You just wrap up my sounds
Wow wow ...
時が来た今
Now that the time has come
Wow wow ...
エゴ放つのさ
I'm releasing my ego
うちにこもって...
Staying inside...
...くるいざけ
...crazy blooming.
エマージェンシー
Emergency,
レイジー
lazy,
さすがにクレイジーな計画は
as expected, a crazy plan
おだぶつ
is dead.
グルグルグルグルと
Round and round and round,
世界は変わらず回っていた
the world kept turning just the same.
ルルル
Lu-lu-lu,
君の視線が
your gaze is
ルルル
lu-lu-lu,
ぼやけて尽きる
getting blurry and fading away.
マリオネットな感情に
To marionette-like emotions,
気付いてしまった
I've finally realized.
相も変わらずジャムる街
In a town that's jamming as usual,
やまぬ愛のバースに
to the verses of endless love,
サマれないで
don't get summed up.
引きこもり絶対ジャスティス
Staying inside is absolute justice.
俺の私のだけの
Inside my own, only my own
檻の中で
cage.
聴き殺してランデブー
A rendezvous of listening to death,
俺の私の目を
until my eyes
君に染まるまで
are dyed in your color.
引きこもり絶対ジャスティス
Staying inside is absolute justice.
俺の私のだけの
Inside my own, only my own
檻の中で
cage.
聴き殺してランデブー
A rendezvous of listening to death,
俺の私の音を
only my sound
君が包むだけ
is wrapped by you.
時がきた今
Now that the time has come,
選び取れ恥を捨てられる
choose the place where you can throw away your shame.
この場所にくるいざけ
Crazy blooming in this place.
はい、ということで！
All right, then!
続けて3曲お聞きいただきましたー！
I just sang three songs in a row!
まずは、えー、インドア系ならトラックメイカー。
First was 'Indoor-kei Nara Trackmaker'.
こちらはね、えー、もう3年前の2019年の2月のバレンタインに
I posted a cover video for that one three years ago,
歌ってみた動画を投稿していて。
on Valentine's Day in February 2019.
そのあと、ユビキタス・デシベルは同じくこれも3年前、
After that was 'Ubiquitous Decibel', also from three years ago,
2019年の12月に投稿した曲です、ありがとう！
a song I posted in December 2019. Thank you!
懐かしいね、本当に。
It really brings back memories.
そして、今さっき披露したのが、
And the song I just performed
えー、つい最近、今年の4月に歌ってみた動画を投稿した
was 'Goodbye Declaration', which I posted a cover of
グッバイ宣言でした！
just recently in April of this year!
みんな見てくれて、本当にありがとう。
Thank you so much for watching it, everyone.
いや、動画もね、たくさん聞いてもらえててね、本当に嬉しかったです。
I'm so happy that the video has been played so many times.
ありがとうございます。ありがとね。
Thank you so much. Thanks.
え、すごいんで、マジでみんなね、聞いてくれてて、
It's amazing how many people have listened to it.
めっちゃ良かったよ、動画って言ってくれててすごいね、嬉しいです、ありがとう。
I'm so glad to hear you guys say the video was great. Thank you.
でね、インドア系ならトラックメイカーはなんとですね、
And, 'Indoor-kei Nara Trackmaker' actually...
600万再生をなんか超えたらしい、最近。
...passed 6 million views recently!
すごいよね！信じられないんだけど。
That's incredible! I can't believe it.
＃あくあ色に染まれ に次ぐ1000万再生がもうすぐ？もうすぐではないか。
Is it almost at 10 million views, following '#Aquairo ni Somare'? Maybe not quite yet.
ありがとうございます。
Thank you very much.
これからもね、いっぱい歌ってみた動画ね、投稿していきたいと思ってるので、
I want to keep posting lots of cover videos,
え、よかったら楽しみにしててくださーい！
so please look forward to them!
お願いしまーす。
Please!
そして、気が付いたら、
And before I knew it,
あくあ城からタイムワープしちゃっている。
I've time-warped from Aqua Castle.
ここはどこ？私は誰？
Where am I? Who am I?
ホロアリーナにあくあ城のセットが、
In the Holo Arena, the Aqua Castle set...
なんかいっぱいある。
...is everywhere!
見て！あ、すごい。
Look! Oh, wow.
お、なんかあくあ仕様の、
It's like an Aqua version...
あ、すごい、すごい、すごい。
...oh, wow, wow, wow.
お、侵食してるめっちゃ。めっちゃすごい、やばいやばい。
It's totally taken over. This is incredible, crazy!
猫とかいんだけど。
There are even cats.
見て、猫がすごい、両方に猫が。
Look, look at the cats. On both sides!
なんか守り神みたいになってない？
Don't they look like guardian deities?
なんと、あとね、えっとね、
And also, um...
あくたん風船もね、こっち側にも、こっちもね、こっちもね、
...there are Akutan balloons on this side, and this side, and this side too,
お、見て、あるの！
look, they're here!
すごい、浮いてる！
Wow, they're floating!
かわいい。
So cute.
いいね。
Nice.
いや、どんどんあくあ色に染まっちゃっている気がする。
I feel like everything is gradually being dyed in Aqua's colors.
いや、もっとね、やっぱね、このステージもね、みんなもね、
I want this stage and all of you
あくあ色に染まってほしいなって思ってます。
to be dyed even more in Aqua's colors.
ということで、続いては、
So, next,
オリジナル曲を歌いたいと思いまーす！
I'm going to sing an original song!
それじゃあ、盛り上がっていきましょー！
All right, let's get pumped up!
For The Win！
For The Win!
For The Win Win Win, For The Win Win Win
信じていてね 大丈夫
please believe in me, it's okay.
あくあ色に染めるよ
I'll dye everything in Aqua's colors,
君と歩くこの未来を
this future I walk with you.
For The Win
作詞/作曲：Neko Hacker
Lyrics/Composition: Neko Hacker
♪ For The Win
自分らしさはどこだろう
Where is my individuality?
自分なりに探しても
Even if I search in my own way
上手くいかないことだらけよ
It's full of things that don't go well
仕方ないな
It can't be helped
空回っちゃって失敗して
Even if I spin my wheels and fail
笑われたって頑張って
Even if I get laughed at, I'll do my best
頑張ってここにいる
Doing my best, I am here
君も同じだよ
You're the same too
諦めなきゃきっと掴めるかな
If I don't give up, I'm sure I can reach it
For the win win win
夢を叫べ今ここで
Shout your dreams, right here, right now
叶えたいものは何?
What is it you want to fulfill?
一つ教えてよ
Tell me one.
For the win win win
信じるだけできるでしょ
Just believing is something you can do, right?
走り切ったその先は
Beyond where you've run to the end
あくあ色の未来よ
Is an aqua-colored future
A!
Q!
U!
A!
行くよ Let's go For the win!
Here we go, Let's go, For the win!
A!
Q!
U!
A!
Yes Aqua For the win!
伝えるのは下手だから
Since I'm not good at conveying things
誤解しないで聞いてよね
Listen without misunderstanding, okay?
私なりの応援だから
Since it's my own way of cheering
わかるでしょ? ねえ
You understand, right? Hey
笑ったって泣いたって
Whether you laugh or cry
一度きり
It's only once
頑張って頑張って
Doing my best, doing my best
ここに来た
I came here
君がいなきゃ絶対たどり着けなかった
Because it's a place I absolutely
場所だから
couldn't have reached without you
For the win win win
今度はギュッと私から
This time, tightly from me
君の背中を強く強く
I'll push your back strongly, strongly
優しくね
and gently, okay?
For the win win win
前を向いて最後も
Looking forward, even at the end
見たことのない世界
A world I've never seen
一緒に旅しようよ
Let's travel together
みんなー!
Everyone!
3周年ライブ来てくれてどうもありがとう!
Thank you so much for coming to the 3rd anniversary live!
いっぱい盛り上がってね!
Get hyped up a lot!
最後まで絶対にコメント切らさないでね!
Definitely don't stop commenting until the end!
よかったらA-Q-U-Aのところ、
If you'd like, at the A-Q-U-A part,
コメントでA-Q-U-A、
say "A-Q-U-A,"
あくあしか勝たんて言ってね!
"Aqua is the best" in the comments!
負けたくない悔し涙が溢れた日でさえも
Even on days when tears of frustration from not wanting to lose overflowed
無駄じゃない私らしさを、作ってく
They are not in vain, they create my individuality
だから大丈夫、大丈夫、心配ないよ
So it's okay, it's okay, don't worry
大丈夫、大丈夫、全力で
It's okay, it's okay, I've kept
走り続けたんだ
running at full power
君ならできるさ
You can do it
喜びも悲しみも分かち合える人がいる
There are people I can share both joy and sadness with
初めて気づいたんだ一人じゃないんだって
I realized for the first time that I'm not alone
For the win win win
仲間たちと叶えたい
I want to fulfill with my friends
夢はきっとこの場所で
Dreams are surely in this place
あくあ色に輝く
Shining in aqua color
A!
Q!
U!
A!
行くよ Let's go For the win!
Here we go, Let's go, For the win!
A!
Q!
U!
A!
Yes Aqua For the win!
ありがとうー!
Thank you!
はーい、ということでー、
Okay, and so,
「For The Win」でした! ありがとう!
that was "For The Win"! Thank you!
ということでですね、次はなんと
So, next,
ゲストが私のこの3Dライブにゲストが
a guest is actually coming to my 3D live,
来てくれるんですが、その前に、
but before that,
ここからはちょっと、ちょっとだけ
from here, I'd like to have a little,
告知タイムをさせていただきたいと思います。
just a little bit of announcement time.
いやね、ちょっとね、あの、
Well, you know, I want to
ちょっとだけ紹介させてほしい、いい?
introduce something just a little bit, okay?
でもさ、やっぱさ、今回3周年だからさ、
But, you know, it's my 3rd anniversary this time,
ちょっとお願い。ちょっと紹介させて。お願い。
so please. Let me introduce it. Please.
いい? いい? ごめんね、いい?
Okay? Okay? Sorry, okay?
ということで、じゃ、え、
And so, then,
告知させていただきたいと思います。
I'd like to make an announcement.
こちら、ドドドン!
This, dododon!
湊あくあ 3周年記念グッズ! イェーイ!
Minato Aqua 3rd Anniversary commemorative goods! Yay!
え、ということでね、活動3周年を記念した
So, a full set commemorating the 3rd anniversary
フルセットがなんと発売されます!
of my activities will actually be released!
このフルセットの中には記念グッズ3種、
In this full set, there are 3 types
そして記念ボイス1種が入っております。
of commemorative goods and 1 type of commemorative voice.
ま、3周年を記念した感じですごい
Well, it's like a 3rd anniversary commemoration
高級感のあるA4複製原画あり、
with a very high-quality A4 reproduction illustration,
また数量限定特典は湊あくあ、
and also the limited quantity bonus is Minato Aqua,
直筆サイン入りポストカード...
signed postcard...
皆さんの、えー直筆サインポストカード付って書いてある。
It says it comes with a hand-signed postcard for you all.
直筆カード書きます、よろしくお願いします。
I'll be signing them, so please look forward to it.
ではね、ちょっと詳しく説明していくと、
Now, let me go into a bit more detail...
湊あくあ 3rd Anniversaryの複製原画というのが、
A reproduction of the original artwork for Minato Aqua's 3rd Anniversary...
なんとですね、今回、えっと出させていただくことになりまして、
is actually going to be released this time!
原画を書いてくださっているのは、えっとトモセシュンサク先生です！
The artist behind the original illustration is Shunsaku Tomose-sensei!
トモセシュンサク先生といえば、やっぱりあの「よう実」のね、案件でもお世話になったりして。
Speaking of Tomose-sensei, he also worked on the "Classroom of the Elite" project.
そう、私も「よう実」大好きなこともあって、なにかとすごくお世話になっておりまして、
Since I'm a huge fan of "Classroom of the Elite", he's helped me out in many ways.
今回はなんとね、3周年のね、ライブのキービジュアルを書いてくださったということで、本当にありがとうございます！
I'm so grateful that he drew the key visual for my 3rd-anniversary live!
でね、すっごい豪華な感じになってるので是非みんなね、買ってください。
It looks incredibly gorgeous, so please be sure to get one.
そして、それ以外にも、あくねこTシャツということで、ドットTシャツだ。
Also, we have the "Aku-Cat T-shirt", which is a dot-style T-shirt.
あくねこドットTシャツということで、ニャニャニャーってありました、あくねこの動画がですね、
Based on the Aku-Cat "Nya-nya-nya" video...
の、えっとイラストがあったよね、私が猫に乗ってさ、宇宙を飛んでいるやつ。
There was an illustration of me riding a cat and flying through space.
あれが、えードットTシャツになって発売されることになりました。
That's being released as a dot-style T-shirt.
めっちゃ可愛いからマジで。すっごい可愛いからマジでね、皆さんチェックしてください。
It's seriously so cute. Please check it out, everyone.
毎日ね、あのドットTシャツで、お外に歩いてください。うん、めっちゃ注目されると思うから。うん。
I hope you wear it every day when you go out. I'm sure it'll get a lot of attention.
そして、えーあくねこのキーホルダーも発売されます。イェーイ！
And we're also releasing an Aku-Cat keychain. Yay!
あくねこキーホルダー100個くらい買って、みんなね、あの痛バッグ作ってくれると嬉しいです。
I'd be happy if you bought 100 keychains and made an "ita-bag" with them.
で、ニャニャニャーって皆でね、あの更新しましょう。
Let's all march along to the "Nya-nya-nya" song together.
そして、なんとですね、私恥ずかしいからあんまりね、ボイスとか出さないんですけれども、
And also, I'm usually too embarrassed to release things like voice packs...
まあね、皆がね、本当にもう早く出してよって、いつ出すの、あくたんってずっと言われておりまして。
But everyone has been asking me when I'll finally release one.
はい、3周年ということでボイスを、えー出させていただくことになりまして。
So, for the 3rd anniversary, I've decided to release a voice pack.
ちょっとマジで恥ずかしいから聞かないでください。聞かないで、これだけは買わなくていいです、皆さん。はい。
Seriously, it's so embarrassing, so please don't listen to it. You don't even have to buy this one.
そして、フルセットご予約の方には、えー枚数限定で、湊あくあ直筆サイン入りポストカードがついてきます！ワーイ！
And for those who pre-order the full set, you'll get a limited-edition hand-signed postcard by me! Yay!
いやね、ずっと配信でやりたいやりたいって言ってたんだけど、なかなかね忙しかったりして実現できなかったので、
I've been saying I wanted to do this for a while, but I've been too busy to make it happen.
この機会にね、いっぱサイン書いちゃいますのでよろしくお願いします！
I'll be signing a lot of them this time, so please look forward to it!
そして、なんと、もう一個告知があります。告知二つ目。
And I have one more announcement. The second one...
湊あくあBIGぬいぐるみが、なんと復活しました！イェーイ！
The Minato Aqua Big Plushie is finally back! Yay!
ということでね、去年、えっと夏に、私のソロワンマンライブで発売されて好評だった、
The Big Plushie that was popular at my solo live last summer...
湊あくあBIGぬいぐるみが再販されることになりました！イェーイ！
is officially being re-released! Yay!
いやね、あの5月に、今年の5月に猫ぬいぐるみが出て、で、あ、あくあぬいぐるみないのかな、とか、
After the cat plushie came out this May, many people were asking for an Aqua plushie,
あ、あくあぬいぐるみあったんだけど、もう売ってないんだ、みたいな声がすっごいあって。
or were sad that it was already sold out.
そう、まあね、去年私のことまだ知らなかった、知らなかったって人にも、えー届けられるようにご用意しました。
So we made it available again for those who didn't know about me back then.
めっちゃ噛んじゃん今日。めっちゃ噛むんだけど今日。ということでね、
I'm stumbling over my words so much today! Anyway...
これがもしかしたら最後のチャンスになるかもしれないので、よかったらお見逃しなく。
This might be your last chance to get one, so don't miss out.
みんなね、いっぱいね抱きしめてください。BIGぬいぐるみをギュって。
Please give the Big Plushie lots of hugs.
あのね、あの殴ったりしちゃダメです。やめてくださいね。ギュって、あの大切にしてください。ということで。
Don't hit it or anything, okay? Please cherish it. Alright then.
よし、全部言えたかな。大丈夫だね。ちょっとも噛んでないね。オッケー、オッケー。
I think I've said everything. I didn't stutter at all. Okay!
詳しい詳細は、えー概要欄を見てもらったり、あとでね、Twitterなどでもお知らせするのでチェックしてください。お願いします！
Check the description for more details, or my Twitter later on. Thank you!
しばらくお待ちください
Please wait a moment
ということで！ここでゲストをお呼びしようと思います！イェーイ！
And now! I'd like to invite a guest! Yay!
ということでね、いや誰だろうねゲスト。
I wonder who the guest could be?
まあね、私の3D配信のゲストになんと初めてなんですけれども、ライブだと初めてなんですけれども、
This is actually the first time I've had a guest for a 3D live performance.
やっぱり初めてのゲストはこの人かなって思ってます。ということでね。
I felt that the first guest just had to be this person.
それでは、えー私の運命の赤い糸で繋がっているお相手、それでは、呼びます。
Now then, the person connected to me by the red thread of fate... let's call her out.
猫又おかゆー！
Nekomata Okayu!
うわあああ！
Uwaaaa!
うわあああ……ドッキ！
Uwaaaa... Dokki!
え？
Eh?
あれ？あれ？あれ？おかいと、おかいと……
Huh? Huh? Huh? Okai-thread, Okai-thread...
はい、どうも！
Alright, hello there!
もぐもぐ〜、おかゆ！
Mogu-mogu~, Okayu!
猫又おかゆです！
It's Nekomata Okayu!
おかゆー！ありがとう来てくれて！
Okayu! Thanks for coming!
チョキチョキ！
Snip snip!
チョキチョキチョキじゃないんだよ！切っちゃだめ！
It's not "snip snip snip"! Don't cut it!
何？おかいと？
What? "Okai-thread"?
おかいとだよ、これ！
This is the "Okai-thread"!
見てて、見えるでしょみんな？ほらほらほら……
Watch, you can see it, right everyone? Look, look, look...
チョキ！
Snip!
ねえ！ちょっと！
Hey! Wait!
もう切っちゃったよ！
You already cut it!
こんなに3年も長く溜めたこの赤い糸が……
This red thread that I've saved for three long years...
まあリサイクルして誰かに使ってよ。
Well, just recycle it and use it on someone else.
なんでだよ！だめだよ！
Why! No way!
運命なんだから、これ！
This is fate!
あくあならたくさんいるよ、いい人。
For Aqua, there are plenty of good people out there.
なんでだよ！ということで……
Why! Anyway...
おかゆが来てくれました！
Okayu has joined us!
あー、どうも。
Ah, hello.
久しぶり、そんなめっちゃ一緒に放送するのは……
It's been a while since we've broadcasted together like this...
めっちゃ久しぶりだね、おかーと。
It's been a long time, Oka-to.
おかーとぶりじゃない？
Not since the "Oka-to" days?
頭が……
My head...
おかーと、おかーと、おかーと……おにぎり……おかーと……頭が……
Oka-to, Oka-to, Oka-to... onigiri... Oka-to... my head...
まあまあまあ、今日はでもおかーとじゃないから。
Now now now, it's not "Oka-to" today.
そうだよね！
That's right!
猫又おかゆだからね！
Because you're Nekomata Okayu!
そうだよ。なんとおかゆはね……
That's right. And Okayu...
今日この3D配信のために……
For today's 3D stream...
レッスンをね、ダンスレッスンを……
She took lessons, dance lessons...
してくれたんだよ！
She did them for me!
そうだよ。もう僕普段はね……
Right. Usually I'm like...
「え、ダンスわかんない、踊れない」って感じなんだけど……
"Eh, I don't know dance, I can't dance," but...
今日はでもね、あくあのね……
But today, for Aqua...
ちょっと切っちゃったけど、大事な3周年だったんで……
I cut it earlier, but it was an important 3rd anniversary...
頑張ってダンスを練習しました！
So I worked hard practicing the dance!
おかゆー！
Okayu!
私のために苦手なダンスレッスンを！
Doing dance lessons you're not good at just for me!
そうだよ。頑張ったんだから。
That's right. I worked hard.
3周年のためにわざわざ来てくれて……
Coming all this way for the 3rd anniversary...
そして歌も覚えてダンスも覚えて、そんな過酷なことを！
And learning the song and the dance, such a grueling thing!
そうだよ、過酷だったよ。
Yeah, it was grueling.
おかゆってば、それってもう……
Okayu, that means you...
私のこと好きすぎ好きすぎ好きすぎー！
Like me too much, too much, too much!
飛んじゃったけど大丈夫？
It flew away, is that okay?
もう使えないけど。
I can't use it anymore though.
ちょっと待って！
Wait a minute!
帰ってきた、帰ってきた！危ね危ね……
It's back, it's back! Phew, that was close...
大丈夫ね、帰ってきたね。
It's okay, it came back.
何その飛んじゃったじゃん。
What was that "it flew away"?
また使うから、これ今年。
You're going to use it again this year?
2021年の私のこと好きすぎ。
My 2021 "like me too much".
やっぱ形を変えていかないとね、どんどん。
I've gotta keep changing its form, bit by bit.
そうだね。
That's right.
飽きられちゃうからね。
People will get tired of it.
そう、飽きられちゃうもね、赤い糸みたいにね。
Yeah, they'll get tired of it, just like the red thread.
飽きられて……
Getting tired of it...
あれ？私には見えるんだけど。あれ？
Wait... I can see it. Huh?
妄想だよ、それは。
That's a delusion.
思い込みの狂気だよ、それ。
It's a madness of self-deception.
思い込みの狂気……頭が……頭が……
Madness of self-deception... my head... my head...
でもね、今日はそんなダンスをずっと頑張ってくれたおかゆに……
But today, for Okayu, who worked so hard on the dance...
プレゼントがあります！
I have a present!
プレゼント？
A present?
何何？どこどこ？
What is it? Where?
みんなでちょっとお気付きかと思うんだけど……
I think everyone might have noticed...
ここ！見て見て、耳のとこ！
Here! Look look, near the ear!
おお！見て見て！
Oh! Look look!
僕のお耳も見て！
Look at my ears too!
僕の耳、おにぎりついてる！
There's an onigiri on my ear!
おにぎりついてる！
An onigiri!
耳そこや！
The ear's there!
耳そこやんか！
The ear's right there!
あれ？なんか……
Huh? Something...
こめかみ、こめかみ……
Temple, temple...
あ！
Ah!
なんかついてる、ちょっと。
There's something there.
ちょっと見えづらいかもだけど……
It might be hard to see, but...
ポンポンがついてる！
There's a pom-pom!
おお！
Oh!
なんとお揃いのイヤモニを……
Guess what? Matching in-ear monitors...
おかゆの分も用意させていただきました！
I prepared a pair for Okayu too!
ありがとう！
Thank you!
おそろっちだよ、これ。
It's a matching set.
おそろっちだ。
A matching set.
どう……見えないけど。
How... I can't see it though.
見えないし、僕は耳がここだから聞こえないけど……
I can't see it, and my ears are here so I can't hear it...
でも嬉しい！
But I'm happy!
あれ？発注ミスたかな、これ。
Huh? Did I mess up the order?
ちょっとここだよ、本当は。
It's actually supposed to be here.
あれ？
Huh?
でもここあるとね、こう……
But if it's there, then...
すんごい長いことなっちゃうからね、デザインの関係で。
It'll get really long, because of the design.
まあ確かにな、ちょっと長くな。
Well, that's true, it would be a bit long.
でもありがとう、嬉しい！
But thank you, I'm happy!
いや、すんごい似合ってるよ、可愛い！
No, it really suits you, so cute!
嬉しい、ありがとう！可愛い！
I'm happy, thanks! So cute!
嬉しいな。
I'm so happy.
ではね、プレゼントも渡したことだし……
Well, now that I've given you the present...
ダンスも頑張ってくれたし……
And you've worked hard on the dance...
やっぱあの曲を一緒に歌おうよ！
Let's sing *that* song together!
あの曲？
That song?
そうそう。
Right, right.
何の曲を歌って踊るんだっけ？
What song were we going to sing and dance to?
あの曲だよ、あの曲。
That song, that one.
愛のラブソング、私たちの。
Our love song of love.
え？教えてもらってもいい？
Eh? Can you tell me?
仕方ないな、おかゆ、こっち来て。
Can't be helped, Okayu, come here.
なんだろう？
What is it?
それじゃ皆様、お待たせいたしました。
Well then everyone, thank you for waiting.
私と猫又おかゆによる……
By me and Nekomata Okayu...
う、うるらら……
U-ururara...
大事なとこ噛んじゃったじゃん！
You messed up the important part!
大丈夫、大丈夫。
It's okay, it's okay.
はい、シャキッと、せーの！
Okay, let's do it right, one, two...!
私と猫又おかゆによる……
By me and Nekomata Okayu...
愛のラブソング……
Our love song of love...
聴いてください。
Please listen.
チューリングラブ！
Turing Love!
あー、恋の定義がわかんない。
Ah, I don't know the definition of love.
まず「好き」って基準もわかんない。
First of all, I don't even know the criteria for "liking".
あーだこーだしてるときが恋らしい
It seems like love is when we're doing this and that
若干、主観、エビデンスプリーズ！
A bit subjective, evidence please!
愛は計算じゃ解けない
Love can't be solved by calculation
まず普通の計算も解けない
First of all, I can't even solve normal calculations
要はそんな状態が愛らしい
In short, that state is lovely
I know 異常な脳内
I know, an abnormal brain
辞書においてQがあってAを出して解けるのに
In a dictionary, there's a Q and an A, and it can be solved, yet
勘違って、間違って、解のないこの気持ちは何だろう
Misunderstanding, making mistakes, what is this feeling with no answer?
検証 is 不明瞭
Verification is unclear
エンジンモーションは相対性ミステイク
Engine motion is a relativity mistake
チューリングラブ 見つめ合ったって解けないメロウ
Turing Love, even if we gaze at each other, it's an unsolvable mellow
What is love? いま 1, 2, 3 で明かそうか
What is love? Now, shall we reveal it on 1, 2, 3?
言葉で生み出す結晶
Crystals created by words
ハートで高鳴るアンサー
An answer throbbing in the heart
測りきって不可確定性 僕らのBPM
Measuring out the uncertainty of our BPM
チューリングラブ チューに舞ったって信じないけど
Turing Love, even if it dances in a kiss, I won't believe it, but
フォーリンラブ いまは ABC すらバグりそうだ
Falling love, now even ABC seems like it's going to bug out
なんでか教えてオイラー
Tell me why, Euler
感想聞かせてフェルマー
Let me hear your thoughts, Fermat
予測不可能生 今触れてみる
Unpredictability, I'm touching it now
さあ証明しよう 間違いのないように
Now let's prove it, so there's no mistake
証明しよう この感情全部全部
Let's prove it, all of these feelings
証明しよう 正解があるなら
Let's prove it, if there's a correct answer
証明しよう シンプルなQ.E.D.
Let's prove it, a simple Q.E.D.
今日こそ証明したい！
I want to prove it today!
目に見えない無理難題を
An invisible, impossible challenge
ASAP 導き出したい
I want to derive it ASAP
たどり着きたい最適解へ
I want to reach the optimal solution
何度空回ったってぶつかっちゃったって
No matter how many times I spin my wheels or collide
不可思議なこのアノマリーを解き明かす過程さ必要条件です
It's the process of unraveling this mysterious anomaly, a necessary condition
三次元(立体)における2点AB間の距離を求めよ
Find the distance between two points A and B in three-dimensional (solid) space
的な感じだと思ってたのに
I thought it was something like that, but
座標も公式も見当たらないし
I can't find the coordinates or the formula
参考資料にも載ってないから君と生み出してみたいじゃん
It's not in the reference materials, so I want to create it with you
三次元(世界)におけるこの気持ちの求め方
The way to find this feeling in the three-dimensional (world)
丸があってバツがあって不安に取ってイコールで
There's a circle, there's a cross, taking it as anxiety, equals
近くなって遠くなって揺れるこの気持ちの針も
The needle of this feeling that swings closer and further
条件 is 明瞭
Condition is clear
Steppin' エモーションは相愛性ミステイク
Steppin' emotion is a mutual love mistake
チューリングラブ 騒ぎ出した胸の痛くなるほど
Turing Love, the commotion in my chest, to the point it hurts
証明は今も確度を増しているようだ
The proof seems to be gaining certainty even now
アイマイな最大仮説を
The vague, maximum hypothesis
いま二人なら実証できそう
Now if it's the two of us, we can likely demonstrate it
チューリングラブ 見つめ合ったって切れないメロウ
Turing Love, even if we gaze at each other, the mellow won't break
What is love? いま 1, 2, 3 で明かそうか
What is love? Now, shall we reveal it on 1, 2, 3?
言葉で生み出す結晶
Crystals created by words
ハートで高鳴るアンサー
An answer throbbing in the heart
測りきって不可確定性 僕らのBPM
Measuring out the uncertainty of our BPM
チューリングラブ チューに舞ったってその因果も
Turing Love, even if it dances in a kiss, its causality
フォーリンラブ いまはエキサイティンまで分かりそうだ
Falling love, now it seems I'll understand up to the excitement
確かめさせてピタゴラス
Let me confirm, Pythagoras
確信させてリーマン
Let me be convinced, Riemann
予測済み改変生 今触れてみる
Already predicted modification, I'm touching it now
さあ証明しよう 間違いのないように
Now let's prove it, so there's no mistake
証明しよう この感情全部全部
Let's prove it, all of these feelings
証明しよう 正解があるなら
Let's prove it, if there's a correct answer
証明しよう 推測を超えて
Let's prove it, going beyond speculation
証明しよう 間違いのないように
Now let's prove it, so there's no mistake
証明しよう この感情全部全部
Let's prove it, all of these feelings
証明しよう 正解があるなら
Let's prove it, if there's a correct answer
証明しよう シンプルなQ.E.D.
Let's prove it, a simple Q.E.D.
チューリング
Turing
わぁーー！おかゆーーー！！
Waaa! Okayu!!!
わぁーー！！
Waaa!!
おかゆーー！！
Okayu!!
おかゆー！私たちってば夫婦になっちゃったんだけど
Okayu! We've basically become a married couple.
じゃあねー！
Bye then!
え、ちょっと待って！待って！待って！待って！
Wait, hold on! Wait! Wait! Wait!
ちょっと！えーーー！！嘘！？行っちゃったんですけど。え？え？
Hey! Whaaat!! No way, she left. Huh? Huh?
おかゆー。いや、おかゆさんでしたー。ありがとうございました。
Okayu... Well, that was Okayu-san! Thank you very much.
またコラボをしましょうねー。え、おかゆとあれ？あれれれれ？
Let's collab again! Eh, with Okayu, and... huh? Huh?
しばらくお待ちください
Please wait for a while
ということで、おかゆとのチューリングラブどうだったかな、みんな？ありがとうね！
So, how did everyone like Turing Love with Okayu? Thank you!
いや、マジで。ちょっと、なんかさ、二人で一緒に踊るって、すごいなんかちょっとさ...
No, seriously. Well, you know, dancing together with someone else is just kind of...
なんか、何？愛の共同作業みたいで、ちょっと、なんかドキドキしちゃったんだけど。
It felt like, what? Like our first collaborative project of love, and it made my heart race a little bit.
みんな、どうだったかな？ありがとうございます！
How was it for everyone? Thank you!
この曲はですね、2020年の9月に投稿していました！
This song, you see, was posted in September of 2020!
いやー、もうね、一年くらい経つのかな？
Man, has it been about a year already?
あっという間だね！
Time flies!
はい、ということで、ここまでお届けしましたが、
Yes, so, we've delivered it up to this point, but...
みんな楽しかったですかー？
...was everyone having fun?
ちょっとおかゆ、すぐ逃げちゃったけど。えー、どうだったかな？
Okayu ran away so quickly, though. Hmm, how was it?
あれ、もうちょっとおしゃべりできるかなーと思ったけども。
Huh, I thought we'd be able to chat for a bit longer.
まあね、あの、いろんな曲歌ったり、おかゆが来てくれたり、本当に楽しいライブだったんですけど。どうだった、楽しかった？
Well, singing various songs, Okayu coming over, it's been a really fun live performance. How was it? Was it fun?
ありがとうね、みんな見てくれて。
Thank you, everyone, for watching.
いや、ね、今年の夏は、なんだか、すごい忙しい気がするんだけど。
Yeah, I feel like this summer is somehow going to be really busy.
まあね、4周年に向けて、まだまだね、
Well, towards the 4th anniversary, there's still a lot...
やりたいこと...
...I want to do...
……まるから
...starting.
みんなともっとね
With everyone, even more...
えー、あくあ色
Uh, 'Aqua color'.
湊あくあのあくあで
With 'Aqua' from Minato Aqua,
ピンクと青で
pink and blue,
いろいろ、なんか、すべて、含めて、あくあ色でね
and including everything else, I'm calling it 'Aqua color'.
いっぱいね、みんなもね、楽しく
I hope everyone enjoys it,
そして、そのあくあ色の輪をもっと広げていけたらいいなって思っておりますので
and that we can further expand this circle of Aqua color.
今後とも、どうぞよろしくお願いします
I look forward to your continued support.
お願いします
Thank you.
まだね、すごく、未熟な私だけれど
I'm still very inexperienced, but
もっと強くなってね、みんなに、こう
I want to become stronger and show everyone
自分の成長していく姿を
how I'm growing.
見せていけたらいいなって思ってるから
So please keep supporting me.
これからも応援よろしくお願いします
I look forward to your continued support.
3周年本当にありがとうございました
Thank you so much for these three years.
ということで
And so,
最後の歌を歌わせていただきたいと思います
I'd like to perform the final song.
最後はですね
The last one is,
えー、新曲をみんなに聴いてもらいたいと思ってます
uh, a new song I want everyone to hear.
えー、3周年の、えー、オリジナル曲の新曲です
It's a new original song for the 3rd anniversary.
えー、この曲は、私の大好きな40mPさんに書き下ろしをしていただきました
This song was written for me by 40mP, whom I love.
すごいね、やっぱ3周年ということで、こう、今までの景色とか
It's amazing. With the 3rd anniversary, reflecting on the scenery so far,
今見えている場所とか
the place I am now,
こう、ホロライブがあって、そして、みんながいてくれて
the fact that Hololive exists, and everyone is here for me,
私がいて
and that I'm here...
なんか、そういう、なんだろう、すごい最初はすっごい寂しかったけど
It was really lonely at first,
今こんなにたくさんの人がいて、こう、すごい多くの人に祝っていただける
but now there are so many people, and it's become a 3rd anniversary
3周年になったなって思ってて
celebrated by so many.
そんなね、えー、4年目を迎えることができたのもみんなのおかげだと思っております
The fact that I can welcome my 4th year is all thanks to you all.
これからもね、みんなとずっと一緒にいたいっていう
From now on, I want to be with everyone forever.
そんな私の気持ちが詰まってる一曲になっているので
This song is filled with those feelings of mine.
よかったら最後まで聴いてください
Please listen to it until the end.
それでは、えー
Well then, uh,
このあとね、えっと、プレミア公開で動画が投稿されると思うので
after this, a video will be posted as a premiere,
ライブのあとも、ぜひチェックしてみてください
so please check it out after the live as well.
素敵なね、すごい手の込んだPVもあるので
There's also a wonderful, very elaborate PV,
よかったら最後まで聴いてくれると嬉しいです
so I'd be happy if you watched it until the end.
ということで
And so,
最後の曲聴いてください
please listen to the final song.
海想列車
'Kaisou Ressha'.
作詞／作曲：40mP
Sea-gaze Train
Lyrics/Composition: 40mP
海想列車　ほんの少しだけ　夢の中で
Sea-gaze Train, just for a little while, in a dream
ゆらゆら　揺られて　波に包まれていたい
Swaying, being rocked, I want to be enveloped by the waves
夢を見てた　あの頃の夢を
I was dreaming, a dream of those days
臆病だった　どこにも行けなかった
I was cowardly, I couldn't go anywhere
変わりたくて　電車に乗り込んだ
Wanting to change, I boarded the train
この世界で一枚だけの切符
The only ticket in this world
路線図も時刻表も　今は空白だけど
Route maps and timetables are still blank, but
窓の向こうには　青より青い水平線
Outside the window is a horizon bluer than blue
海想列車　ほんの少しだけ　怖いけれど
Sea-gaze Train, just for a little while, though it's scary
走り出した夢は　もう止まらない
The dream that started running won't stop anymore
世界なんて　考えてみても　わからないから
Because I won't understand even if I think about the world
目の前に広がる　この景色を見ていたい
I want to see this scenery spreading before my eyes
夢を見てた　あの頃の夢を
I was dreaming, a dream of those days
一人じゃきっと　ここまで来れなかった
I surely couldn't have come this far alone
途中の駅で　降り出しそうな時にも
Even when I felt like getting off at a station along the way
君がいつもそばにいてくれた
You were always there by my side
ごめんねもありがとうも　まだ言い足りてないよ
I haven't said 'sorry' or 'thank you' enough yet
私のペースで　不器用なりに伝えていくから
At my own pace, in my own clumsy way, I'll convey them to you
...世界へ
...to the world.
空白の路線図は今この手で
The blank route map, now in my hands,
作り上げていく
I'll keep building it.
海想列車 夢から醒めた
Reminiscent train, I woke up from a dream.
懐かしくて
It felt so nostalgic.
変わらない想いをそっと抱きしめた
I softly embraced my unchanging feelings.
笑い合って 手を取り合って
Laughing together, holding hands,
同じ時を過ごした
we spent the same time together.
君と これからもずっと
With you, from now on and forever.
海想列車 もう怖くはない
Reminiscent train, I'm not afraid anymore.
無我夢中で
So absorbed,
駆け抜けた日々は夢じゃないから
the days we ran through aren't a dream.
正解なんて考えてみても
Even if I try to think about the right answer,
分からないけど
I don't know it, but
目の前に広がる
spreading out before my eyes,
この景色を見ていたい ああ
I want to keep watching this scenery, ah.
君と一緒に
Together with you,
この景色を見ていたい
I want to keep watching this scenery.
メンバーシップでよかったら3D配信するので見に来てね！
I'll be doing a 3D stream on membership, so please come watch if you'd like!
後ほどお会いしましょう！ということで
I'll see you later! So,
おつあくあでしたー！
Otsuaqua!
4年目もよろしくねー！
Please support me in my 4th year too!
見てくれてありがとう！ 4年目もよろしくね！
Thanks for watching! Please support me in my 4th year too!